<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>BCLExtensions on csMACnz&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://csmacnzblog.github.io/tags/bclextensions/</link>
    <description>Recent content in BCLExtensions on csMACnz&#39;s Blog</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://csmacnzblog.github.io/favicon.png</url>
      <title>csMACnz&#39;s Blog</title>
      <link>https://csmacnzblog.github.io</link>
    </image>
    <ttl>1440</ttl>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-nz</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2015 15:25:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://csmacnzblog.github.io/tags/bclextensions/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Introducing BCLExtensions</title>
      <link>https://csmacnzblog.github.io/post/introducing-bclextensions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2015 15:25:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://csmacnzblog.github.io/post/introducing-bclextensions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It has been a pipe-dream of mine for a while to have my very own C# extensions library. Well now I do.  I&amp;rsquo;ve been chipping away at a library on github for ages (my init commit was &lt;strong&gt;15 Sep 2012!&lt;/strong&gt;) and it is finally a real thing! I&amp;rsquo;ve got a V1.0.0, a Nuget package, and even 100% coverage. I even have the &lt;a href=&#34;https://scan.coverity.com/projects/3770&#34;&gt;coverity report&lt;/a&gt; running, although it&amp;rsquo;s taken so long that I don&amp;rsquo;t have anything to worry about right now.  So far there are 24 Extensions available to use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a bonus, my library is a PCL using profile 328, which pretty much means it will work with any C# application you are writting.  I even have it building and running all my test on &lt;a href=&#34;https://travis-ci.org/csMACnz/BCLExtensions&#34;&gt;Travis-CI&lt;/a&gt; (252 tests and counting).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please feel free to grab the nuget at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nuget.org/packages/BCLExtensions&#34;&gt;nuget.org/packages/BCLExtensions&lt;/a&gt; and check the source as &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/csMACnz/BCLExtensions&#34;&gt;github.com/csMACnz/BCLExtensions&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next steps: keep knocking out the extensions from my wishlist, get resharper&amp;rsquo;s inspectcode.exe command-line tool running, and tidy up all the documentation onto the wiki and maybe on of the docs services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have suggestions? Or are there extensions on my list that you want me to prioritise? Open an issue and let me know.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>