<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Conference on csMacnz&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://csmacnzblog.github.io/categories/conference/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Conference on csMacnz&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-nz</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 May 2019 10:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://csmacnzblog.github.io/categories/conference/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>µCon 2019 - Day 3</title>
      <link>https://csmacnzblog.github.io/post/mucon-2019-part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2019 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://csmacnzblog.github.io/post/mucon-2019-part2/</guid>
      <description>Good morning day 3. So much to absorb already from Day 1 and 2but it isn&amp;rsquo;t over yet.
This morning&amp;rsquo;s Keynote &amp;ldquo;Crossing the River by Feeling the Stones&amp;rdquo; from Simon Wardleyis a must see. This was a very educational look at the value of maps, and the importance of knowing the landscape, looking at Evolutionary Flow and not just Process Flow when looking at optimisations. I would recommend the talk from Susanne Kaiser &amp;ldquo;Preparing for a future Microservices journey&amp;rdquo; from the day before as a nice companion to this keynote talk, as she used &amp;ldquo;Wardley Maps&amp;rdquo; to specifically look at the evolution towards microservices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>µCon 2019 - Day 1 &amp; 2</title>
      <link>https://csmacnzblog.github.io/post/mucon-2019-part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2019 20:05:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://csmacnzblog.github.io/post/mucon-2019-part1/</guid>
      <description>After a restful night at a London hotel (I learned my lesson from the last time I came in for a London conference) coffee and breakfast at the Business Design Centre in London, muCon 2019 kicks off. muCon (or µCon) is a Conference on Microservices, DDD &amp;amp; Software Architecture. From what I gather, this year for the first time it is an amalgamation of a DDD and Microservices conference into one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My first DDD Event and how I made the decision to work a 16 hour Saturday</title>
      <link>https://csmacnzblog.github.io/post/my-first-ddd-event-and-how-i-made-the-decision-to-work-a-16-hour-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2018 02:36:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://csmacnzblog.github.io/post/my-first-ddd-event-and-how-i-made-the-decision-to-work-a-16-hour-day/</guid>
      <description>In my hand, I have a couple of train tickets. The reservations indicate that I left the house at 5 am Saturday morning to make the first train from Birmingham to Cambridge, and wouldn&amp;rsquo;t get home again until 9 pm. And that is exactly what I did.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been making more of an effort this year to attend conferences and community events. I had a blast at NDC Oslo 2018 (1,2) meeting some amazing people, off the back of that I heard about Birmingham Alt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Geeking out on a Saturday at the Birmingham Alt.Net Unconference</title>
      <link>https://csmacnzblog.github.io/post/geeking-out-at-altnetbrum-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jul 2018 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://csmacnzblog.github.io/post/geeking-out-at-altnetbrum-2018/</guid>
      <description>Unlike some unfortunate people who found out on the day and missed out, I had the opportunity to attend the Alt.Net Unconference in Birmingham this Saturday.
Now I know some of you think Saturday Conferences are too far outside your work time. But hear me out on this first. This is a free event, which means no expensive expense approval. It included lunch so no personal cost apart from transport to get there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NDC Oslo 2018 - Day 2 &amp; 3</title>
      <link>https://csmacnzblog.github.io/post/ndc-oslo-2018-part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jun 2018 20:16:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://csmacnzblog.github.io/post/ndc-oslo-2018-part2/</guid>
      <description>Day 2 Day 2 of NDC Oslo. A bit less productive than the first. I needed a longer lunch and missed a couple of slots, but made the most of talking to some of the speakers for a bit over the break. There is so much going on that it just felt necessary.
Never-the-less, I did still pack in a few good choices throughout the day.
Rise of the Tech Influencer First up was Michelle Sandfordwith her talk &amp;ldquo;Rise of the Tech Influencer - Small steps you can take to increase your reach&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NDC Oslo 2018 - Day 1</title>
      <link>https://csmacnzblog.github.io/post/ndc-oslo-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2018 06:34:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://csmacnzblog.github.io/post/ndc-oslo-2018/</guid>
      <description>With 10 streams on, there has been a lot to choose from at NDC in Oslo. But as day one ends, I&amp;rsquo;ve now voted with my feet. And since I can&amp;rsquo;t be in two places at once (though the overflow does technically make this possible) these are the decisions I made, and a few takeaways from each.
Day 1 I was pretty much jumping from one session to the next today but had a little time to walk the stalls first.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS Summit London 2018</title>
      <link>https://csmacnzblog.github.io/post/aws-summit-london-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 May 2018 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://csmacnzblog.github.io/post/aws-summit-london-2018/</guid>
      <description>I recently attended the AWS Summit in London and thought I would give some notes on the event from my perspective.
As a developer working for a company that uses AWS, there was plenty to get out of an event such as this, and the free attendance makes a great business case to get the time to go.
I really enjoyed the schedule of talks that I attended, and the keynote was a good overview of the state of things as AWS, with some exciting insight into partners in Automotive, and Healthcare.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Global Day of Coderetreat 2015. Done.</title>
      <link>https://csmacnzblog.github.io/post/global-day-of-coderetreat-2015-done/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2015 18:35:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://csmacnzblog.github.io/post/global-day-of-coderetreat-2015-done/</guid>
      <description>It was another great year being involved in the Global Day of Coderetreat for 2015. This was my first year hosting, and it was great fun planning the exercises and running the day. With 16 people turning up, we had a nice mix of student developers, junior developers from various different Software Consultancies around Wellington, and a couple of Seasoned Vets of the GCDR who are known faces from the .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Global Day of Coderetreat 2015 is here</title>
      <link>https://csmacnzblog.github.io/post/global-day-of-code-retreat-2015-is-here/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2015 18:22:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://csmacnzblog.github.io/post/global-day-of-code-retreat-2015-is-here/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s that time of year again for Programmers the world over to gather together and practice their art. Yes, It&amp;rsquo;s the 2015 Global Day of Code Retreat on Saturday 14th November, and once again I have found myself involved. 4 years ago I attended my first GDCR in Wellington and it was great fun. Now, having stepped in to help facilitate last year, I have stepped up to Host it, with the help of a few of my colleagues as Xero.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
