<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>HTPC on csMacnz&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://csmacnzblog.github.io/categories/htpc/</link>
    <description>Recent content in HTPC on csMacnz&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-nz</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Mar 2010 05:54:01 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://csmacnzblog.github.io/categories/htpc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>From MythTV to Windows Media Center</title>
      <link>https://csmacnzblog.github.io/post/from-mythtv-to-windows-media-center/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Mar 2010 05:54:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://csmacnzblog.github.io/post/from-mythtv-to-windows-media-center/</guid>
      <description>I recently decided to make the leap from Ubuntu and open source MythTV to the professional product, Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s Windows Media Center. Why you may ask? Well to be honest I moved and lost my Freeview reception, then came to the conclusion that without that I no longer had any real use for the machine. But also I have recently become a Windows developer and and using Linux less and less. My Windows partitions on my other machines are getting booted more and more, and with windows 7 out (and getting my hands on a couple of copies) I thought it a good time to change focus and try another media PC software out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>XBOX 360, a new use for my tversity</title>
      <link>https://csmacnzblog.github.io/post/xbox-360-a-new-use-for-my-tversity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 May 2008 04:21:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://csmacnzblog.github.io/post/xbox-360-a-new-use-for-my-tversity/</guid>
      <description>About a month back I finally had enough cash to buy myself an xbox 360. I even managed to get three games with it which was a bonus, since it would be a while before I could afford more. Viva Pinata, Forza Motorsport 2 and Assassin&amp;rsquo;s Creed were the three games I got with it, and within a week I also had a copy of Halo 3, the main reason why anyone would get an xbox over a playstation (right?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tversity On Linux with vmware</title>
      <link>https://csmacnzblog.github.io/post/tversity-on-linux-with-vmware/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2008 22:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://csmacnzblog.github.io/post/tversity-on-linux-with-vmware/</guid>
      <description>My struggles with TVersity have come to an end for the moment, and I&amp;rsquo;m quite happy with that. After struggling for many hours to get it working under wine on my ubuntu machine, I decided to try out vmware running virtual windows xp. it took all of a couple of hours, most of which was a windows installation, and i had TVersity working from virtual xp on my ubuntu box. It works well enough to be able to stream music to my psp without any skipping, and I have even tested it with streaming video to an xbox 360.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TVersity media streaming</title>
      <link>https://csmacnzblog.github.io/post/tversity-media-streaming/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2008 02:52:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://csmacnzblog.github.io/post/tversity-media-streaming/</guid>
      <description>About a year ago I bought myself a psp off of the local auction website TradeMe, New Zealand&amp;rsquo;s answer to eBay, and have since used it mostly for listening to music and not a lot else. Sure I&amp;rsquo;ve used it for gaming, and struggled with using it for the internet, and just recently I&amp;rsquo;ve started watching videos (though due to the hassle of converting them not many), but music has been its main use.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
