<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ndcoslo on csMACnz&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://csmacnzblog.github.io/tags/ndcoslo/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ndcoslo on csMACnz&#39;s Blog</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://csmacnzblog.github.io/favicon.png</url>
      <title>csMACnz&#39;s Blog</title>
      <link>https://csmacnzblog.github.io</link>
    </image>
    <ttl>1440</ttl>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-nz</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Jun 2018 20:16:48 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://csmacnzblog.github.io/tags/ndcoslo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>NDC Oslo 2018 - Day 2 &amp; 3</title>
      <link>https://csmacnzblog.github.io/post/ndc-oslo-2018-part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jun 2018 20:16:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://csmacnzblog.github.io/post/ndc-oslo-2018-part2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;day-2&#34;&gt;Day 2&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Day 2 of NDC Oslo. A bit less productive than the first. I needed a longer lunch and missed a couple of slots, but made the most of talking to some of the speakers for a bit over the break. There is so much going on that it just felt necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Never-the-less, I did still pack in a few good choices throughout the day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;rise-of-the-tech-influencer&#34;&gt;Rise of the Tech Influencer&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First up was &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/msandfor&#34;&gt;Michelle Sandford&lt;/a&gt; with her talk &amp;ldquo;Rise of the Tech Influencer - Small steps you can take to increase your reach&amp;rdquo;. I had been twitter-stalking Michelle a bit the last few days leading up and into NDC, and it turns out that may have been the right idea based on some of the points through her talk. I need to take some advice to update my profile, get a picture of me instead of my avatar (done! Thanks Michelle!) so that I can get recognised more easily, and promote more of my writing better through social networks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t get a chance to catch her at the end but needed to find her again before the end of the week for a decent chat, which I managed at the Social drinks on Thursday Night, and between sessions on Friday.  Sorry I didn&amp;rsquo;t get a final goodbye before the day&amp;rsquo;s end, Michelle!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;implementing-authentication-and-authorization-with-aspnet-core-2&#34;&gt;Implementing Authentication and Authorization with ASP.Net Core 2&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A great talk by &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/zerokoll&#34;&gt;Chris Klug&lt;/a&gt; on Auth in ASP.Net Core. Now I have done this before, and the hard way because I was connecting Auth to GitHub. But it is fair to say that I didn&amp;rsquo;t really understand what I was doing at the time. However the clear incremental approach Chris took explaining each couple of lines as he went made it well worth revisiting something not entirely new to me. Recommended to anyone trying to do Auth with AspNetCore 2.X.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;lunch&#34;&gt;Lunch&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After so many talks packed so tight across a day and a half, I felt it necessary to take a break for a long lunch, and had to miss a couple of slots. This gave me the chance to sit and have lunch with a lovely group of speakers. Also just reading a title of &amp;ldquo;Quantum Computing&amp;rdquo; made my head hurt for at least an hour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;adapting-aspnet-core-mvc-to-your-needs&#34;&gt;Adapting ASP.NET Core MVC to your Needs&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Competing timeslots with Jon Skeet is hard work, but I decided that Dates and Timezones wasn&amp;rsquo;t as immediately necessary to me as AspNetCore is. (This later may have been regretted as I ran late towards a train leaving Oslo, realising my calendar appointment wasn&amp;rsquo;t timezone adjusted. - Made it though!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I went along to see &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/filip_woj&#34;&gt;Filip W&lt;/a&gt; talk about what is new in AspNetCore 2.1 and MVC. I learned a bunch of new features, especially extension points and convention based patterns that will help reduce the MVC boiler-plate we have used in the last few releases, thanks to more convention over configuration enhancements, and the ability to customise them, too. Worth looking at if you are wanting to understand customising AspNetCore 2.1, or just to learn what Cargo-Cult code you can now remove.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;finding-your-service-boundaries&#34;&gt;Finding your service boundaries&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Finding your service boundaries - A practical guide&amp;rdquo; was an interesting talk from &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/adamralph&#34;&gt;Adam Ralph&lt;/a&gt; talking over some of the finer points of using data-first approaches to building up your service boundaries. By avoiding doing Entity-First, or even naming things, we can avoid mistakes in design caused by these names.  I don&amp;rsquo;t do the concept justice but if you are doing a lot of data-modeling for your services to get the Architecture right, this is one to take a look at. A lot of familiar principles of coupling and cohesion, applied to the domain of Micro Services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;containers-in-production&#34;&gt;Containers in Production&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rounding out the day, right before the beer started, flowing was a very educational talk from &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/DavidOstrovsky&#34;&gt;David Ostrovsky&lt;/a&gt;. The full title is &amp;ldquo;Containers in Production: It&amp;rsquo;s Like Orchestrating Cats&amp;rdquo;.  This was a great real-world overview of using Kubernetes Clusters in production, for developers.  While he covers a few DevOps-y points towards the end, most of the operational points were nicely dev-centric and his points on health-checks and logging were spot-on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had a quick chat with him afterwards about Containers and their health ping. He had stated that he adds checks for dependencies inside his health-check endpoint. I raised the concern that this might cause a cascading failure if a downstream service went down. He made the very valid point that firstly there is a cooldown. It will still report 200 until a service has been down for a period, then start complaining that it can&amp;rsquo;t do its job. This way, transient downstream issues won&amp;rsquo;t take out the upstream components.  Secondly, if you actually need the other services to do your work, and you don&amp;rsquo;t have graceful degradation and short timeouts, then stopping this service is probably better. Your app and its consumers will then fail fast, rather than hang requests, or worse, produce incorrect results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To round that out, I later learned that Kubernetes has a backoff strategy for restarting instances, which would stop it thrashing in the above failing health check case (which I am yet to locate in AWS ECS).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;pubconf&#34;&gt;PubConf&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Honourable mention goes to PubConf. That&amp;rsquo;s all I want to say on the matter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;day-3&#34;&gt;Day 3&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The nature of a good conference is the opportunity to mingle for drinks the last night before the last day. Which means rather than putting together an update of day 2, the meeting of speakers and other like-minded developers takes priority over writing this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Never-the-less, here we are on day 3, the final day of NDC Oslo 2018.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first session was replaced with a late breakfast, and a chance to try out the overflow room. It&amp;rsquo;s hard to judge talks well from switching between them, so I will have to revisit this and reserve judgement here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-hello-world-show-live&#34;&gt;The Hello World Show LIVE&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have to say that I&amp;rsquo;m not familiar with their show, but I was familiar with some of the guests. In almost a lightning-talk style, each guest gave a quick presentation, and these we all very entertaining and educational at the same time. This was educational and entertaining at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After this, I think It is only fair I take a look at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCh1MAMXrvKK_C_piVgOFOAg&#34;&gt;The Hello World Show&lt;/a&gt; on YouTube.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;deconstructing-priviledge&#34;&gt;Deconstructing Priviledge&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/pati_gallardo&#34;&gt;Patricia Aas&lt;/a&gt; presented her talk on &amp;ldquo;Deconstructing Privilege&amp;rdquo;. I learned a lot. This is brain-altering stuff. In a good way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope I can convey this in the way it is intended and not get misunderstood, but I walked out in silent contemplation which lasted several minutes before I could engage in another conversation. Very thought-provoking, and I hope it had the desired effect of me achieving conscious incompetence at least.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also had recommendations to check out Arthur Doler&amp;rsquo;s &#39; Let&amp;rsquo;s Talk About Mental Health&#39; that was on at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;kubernetes-for-net-developers&#34;&gt;Kubernetes for .Net developers&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/ShahidDev&#34;&gt;Shahid Iqbal&lt;/a&gt; was a nice companion talk to attended following David Ostrovsky&amp;rsquo;s Cat-Herding from the day before. A bit more hands-on with Kubernetes demos, templates and scripts, including demonstrating switching between dev-machine to cloud with the same &lt;code&gt;kubectl&lt;/code&gt; toolchain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;not-a-magic&#34;&gt;Not a magic&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Not a magic: What to expect from Machine Learning projects&amp;rdquo; was co-presented by &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/KatyaGeek&#34;&gt;Katya Mustafina&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/illumikko&#34;&gt;Natalia An&lt;/a&gt;. This was my wildcard for the day, getting a taste for ML and how it is done. I now have a much better understanding of the Machine Learning development cycle, and how complicated and time-consuming it can be to produce something useful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;12-factor-microservices&#34;&gt;12 Factor MicroServices&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite the fact that Troy Hunt was speaking in the other room, I felt I had more to benefit from finding out more about this &lt;a href=&#34;https://12factor.net/&#34;&gt;12 Factor&lt;/a&gt; stuff, from someone who practically follows the principles himself. &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/pondidum&#34;&gt;Andy Davies&lt;/a&gt; talked us through the 12 principles that make up 12-factor, with a few his own preferences and variations along the way, on how he uses them to source control, build, test and release pipeline his software applications.  Nothing too earth-shattering, but a good revision of the basics, things that might seem obvious to some, but not all of us do it. There was at least one point from this talk that I can use to try out as part of our iterative improvement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;again&#34;&gt;Again?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Would I attend again? Without question. Well, one question. Can I afford it? Chances are if I had to come all the way from New Zealand or Australia it would be a bit of a mission and would hurt the wallet. However, if NDC Sydney is even half as good as this then it would be highly recommended. (Though I hear pre-sales may have just ended.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks again to all the great speakers and attendees for their hallway conversions. This really makes a conference like this what it is.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NDC Oslo 2018 - Day 1</title>
      <link>https://csmacnzblog.github.io/post/ndc-oslo-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2018 06:34:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://csmacnzblog.github.io/post/ndc-oslo-2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With 10 streams on, there has been a lot to choose from at NDC in Oslo.  But as day one ends, I&amp;rsquo;ve now voted with my feet. And since I can&amp;rsquo;t be in two places at once (though the overflow does technically make this possible) these are the decisions I made, and a few takeaways from each.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;day-1&#34;&gt;Day 1&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was pretty much jumping from one session to the next today but had a little time to walk the stalls first.  A quick chat with the Guys from Microsoft, Octopus Deploy and a few stickers from some other stalls such as Twilio and JetBrains.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;keynote&#34;&gt;Keynote&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/MadsTorgersen&#34;&gt;Mads Torgersen&lt;/a&gt; gave a great Keynote walking us through the 50 year history of Object Oriented Programming which covered many languages not seen much today, all the way up to Javascript and C# (and others) still used today, with a nice overview of which features were &amp;ldquo;invented&amp;rdquo; with each advancement.  This included interesting syntax inventions of &amp;ldquo;C-mula&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;C-ta&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;c-8&#34;&gt;C# 8&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jonskeet&#34;&gt;Jon Skeet&lt;/a&gt; joined Mads Torgersen on stage to run through some beta builds of Visual Studio to demonstrate the coming soon features of C# in version 8. Honourable mentions I am looking forward to are the new switch pattern matching, Nullable Reference Type (&lt;code&gt;string?&lt;/code&gt;), and the new &amp;ldquo;Dammit!&amp;rdquo; operator.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I managed to find myself sitting next to Jon at a talk later in the day, and am very happy to have had a quick chat and got a Selfie with him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;implementing-a-clean-architecture-in-net-core&#34;&gt;Implementing a Clean Architecture in .Net Core&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/icooper&#34;&gt;Ian Cooper&lt;/a&gt; from Huddle walking us through Ports and Adapters in an evolutionary step by step way, evolving through an application while also going through the history of the architecture from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cs.sjsu.edu/~pearce/modules/patterns/enterprise/ecb/ecb.htm&#34;&gt;Entity-Control-Boundary&lt;/a&gt; back to Hexagonal and Ports and Adapters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I must check out his library &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/BrighterCommand/Brighter&#34;&gt;Brighter&lt;/a&gt; for its CQRS Command Dispatcher support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-power-of-roslyn&#34;&gt;The power of Roslyn&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After lunch, I was able to find out more about (and how easy it is) to make Roslyn inspecters and refactors from &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/kuhlenhuth&#34;&gt;Kasey Uhlenhuth&lt;/a&gt;. Another must try to add to the list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;give-it-a-rest&#34;&gt;Give it a REST&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I met &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/westleyl&#34;&gt;Liam Westley&lt;/a&gt; the night before and his elevator pitch and some conversion over beer lead me to make this a must-see. Also from Huddle and works with Ian Cooper, the full title &amp;ldquo;Give it a REST - Tips for designing and consuming public APIs&amp;rdquo; was a nice mix of tips and tricks for building, consuming, and maintaining REST APIs in a real, pragmatic way. Full of example horror stories from in and around his own company, it was full of valuable points to take away and start using.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One point of note, was using a nested PUT on a resource to do patch actions in a lightweight way (such that a record status update would be a PUT to &amp;ldquo;record/123/status&amp;rdquo;). Pragmatic. Also, asynchronous requests using &lt;code&gt;202 Accepted&lt;/code&gt;, using &lt;code&gt;429 TooManyRequests&lt;/code&gt; for throttling, and using cache-related headers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Apologies to &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/PeterHilton&#34;&gt;Peter Hilton&lt;/a&gt; for missing yours that was at the same time, it is going to be a must see when I get access to the recordings. Beautiful code: typography and visual programming. - &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/it_vegard/status/1006891857073377280&#34;&gt;see twitter&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;reinventing-mvc-pattern-for-web-programming-with-f&#34;&gt;Reinventing MVC pattern for web programming with F#&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a bit of a change, while still following the AspNetCore theme, I went and watched &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/k_cieslak&#34;&gt;Krzysztof Cieślak&lt;/a&gt; (Chris), dubbed OSS Troublemaker. He talked about his Open Source project &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/SaturnFramework/Saturn&#34;&gt;Saturn&lt;/a&gt; which is built on top of &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/giraffe-fsharp/Giraffe&#34;&gt;Giraffe&lt;/a&gt; which in turn is built as an F# Library on top of AspNetCore. Saturn is an &amp;ldquo;MVC&amp;rdquo; library in F#, written to give you the power and performance leveraged from AspNetCore, but trying to keep in mind the concept of the Pit of Success, to make it easy to use, and easy to get starting as a new developer, while benefiting from the principles of MVC, and the power and productivity of F#.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So many new tools to explore, and we are only one day in!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;an-opinionated-approach-to-aspnet-core&#34;&gt;An Opinionated Approach to ASP.NET Core&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/OdeToCode&#34;&gt;K. Scott Allen&lt;/a&gt; gave us some opinions. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find anything too much to argue with, which probably means I should have gone to a different talk instead. However, his points were interesting to hear from someone else, nonetheless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use &amp;ldquo;Features&amp;rdquo; folders to structure areas of your application functionality (keep Use-Case centric code together essentially); Async suffix has served its purpose, and is no longer really that relevant (we can stop mandating it); There is a button in Visual Studio to toggle the Solution Explorer between classic view, and filesystem view; put your build and helper scripts in your repository; have samples in your repository; put your solution at the top level of your repo.  As I say, lots of stuff that I would probably advocate as well if you asked me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The one throw-away comment that stuck with me was actually &amp;ldquo;I wish there was a way to put my tests in here too&amp;rdquo; in relation to being beside the code in the Feature beside the feature&amp;rsquo;s code.  This is something I have to go away and see if it can be done with a little MSBuild magic, and maybe even extracted to a target file in a NuGet package, perhaps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;one-down&#34;&gt;One down&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow is day 2, and there will another ~70 talks to get down to 7 which I should be able to give another debrief on as well. It may take up until tomorrow to make that decision, though.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>