<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>kotlin on csMACnz&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://csmacnzblog.github.io/tags/kotlin/</link>
    <description>Recent content in kotlin on csMACnz&#39;s Blog</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://csmacnzblog.github.io/favicon.png</url>
      <title>csMACnz&#39;s Blog</title>
      <link>https://csmacnzblog.github.io</link>
    </image>
    <ttl>1440</ttl>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-nz</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 May 2021 17:42:06 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://csmacnzblog.github.io/tags/kotlin/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Kotlin, TeamCity and reflection</title>
      <link>https://csmacnzblog.github.io/post/kotlin-teamcity-and-reflection/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 May 2021 17:42:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://csmacnzblog.github.io/post/kotlin-teamcity-and-reflection/</guid>
      <description><p>I&rsquo;ve been getting stuck into upskilling in Kotlin. Mostly for TeamCity build automation and trying to produce quality tested code in a space where automation was retrofitted in.</p>
<p>Today&rsquo;s fun little problem was the error message:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Runtime error RootProjectId: kotlin.reflect.jvm.internal.impl.builtins.KotlinBuiltIns$3[92]: java.lang.AssertionError: Built-in class kotlin.Any is not found</p>
</blockquote>
<p>The canonical stack overflow question that (at the time of writing this) had no answer: <a href="https://stackoverflow.com/questions/67199546/why-am-i-getting-java-lang-assertionerror-built-in-class-kotlin-any-is-not-fou">https://stackoverflow.com/questions/67199546/why-am-i-getting-java-lang-assertionerror-built-in-class-kotlin-any-is-not-fou</a></p>
<p>The repro was the simplest piece of code in the end. I was even able to point it at a teamcity class over my own (<code>Project</code>):</p>
<pre><code>import kotlin.reflect.full.declaredMemberProperties

val props = Project::class.declaredMemberProperties
</code></pre>
<p>(For reference, i tried a few version configurations, but they were mainly kotlin version 1.3.31 teamcity version 2019.2 and kotlin version 1.4.31 and teamcity version 202.2.2)</p>
<p>At this point in time and with some further testing, I&rsquo;ve come to the conclusion that <strong>reflection just isn&rsquo;t supported on teamcity with Kotlin</strong>. I&rsquo;ve found one or two Issue links to back that up too: <a href="https://youtrack.jetbrains.com/issue/TW-59901">https://youtrack.jetbrains.com/issue/TW-59901</a></p>
<p>(¬_¬ )</p>
<p>If anyone else managed to find a solution that works, or if any future version adds the missing puzzle pieces that make this work, I would be greatful to hear.</p>
<p>For now, I have replaced the reflection with good ol' verbose fragile code.</p>
<p>Luckily, the tests allow reflection no problem so at least the fragility of this case is covered. If someone adds a property then at least a test fails until the verbose code had been amended.</p>
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>