<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Personal on csMACnz&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://csmacnzblog.github.io/categories/personal/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Personal on csMACnz&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-nz</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2008 22:54:55 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://csmacnzblog.github.io/categories/personal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Flatting: &#39;O&#39; week Arrivals</title>
      <link>https://csmacnzblog.github.io/post/flatting-o-week-arrivals/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2008 22:54:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://csmacnzblog.github.io/post/flatting-o-week-arrivals/</guid>
      <description>The flat is finally full of people and things are starting to settle down and level off a bit. It is now a week after &amp;lsquo;O&amp;rsquo; week, the biggest week on the University of Otago&amp;rsquo;s calender where all the students arrive back in dunedin, move into their flats and their Halls of Residence, and the orientation begins. Lectures have now begun and things are quieter, it is hard to tell that only a week ago everything was different.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Flatting Experience Continues</title>
      <link>https://csmacnzblog.github.io/post/the-flatting-experience-continues/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2008 02:26:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://csmacnzblog.github.io/post/the-flatting-experience-continues/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s all starting to come together now. With power, phone and internet all connected and up and running, we can finally start living in our own flat. It has taken almost two weeks but finally we have our internet connected, and I can start using my computer more productively. As a Computing student, I really can say that I need the internet for my studies, and i can also claim that playing games helps my course, but of course this is easier to claim when I can do research on the internet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Flatting Experience</title>
      <link>https://csmacnzblog.github.io/post/the-flatting-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2008 02:47:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://csmacnzblog.github.io/post/the-flatting-experience/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;ll I have officially been living in my flat for over a week, my first flat that i have lived in away from home, and so far I&amp;rsquo;ve enjoyed it. OK, so I haven&amp;rsquo;t really spent a great deal of time there, what with working all day and having a social life, but despite that it has been good so far. Maybe i should take a step back for a second.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An ode to blogging</title>
      <link>https://csmacnzblog.github.io/post/an-ode-to-blogging/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2008 04:38:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://csmacnzblog.github.io/post/an-ode-to-blogging/</guid>
      <description>A friend emailed me today, and told me a grand epic that was a day in his life, and my first response to him was &amp;lsquo;that story is blog-worthy, share it with the world why don&amp;rsquo;t you?&amp;rsquo;.
It&amp;rsquo;s become more and more self-evident, that the world is full of linguistically capable, and even exceptional writers, many of whom would never have had a chance to use their gifts and let their unique genius be heard by others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s try this again</title>
      <link>https://csmacnzblog.github.io/post/lets-try-this-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jan 2008 21:09:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://csmacnzblog.github.io/post/lets-try-this-again/</guid>
      <description>So I was on holiday, and over that time i didn&amp;rsquo;t add a single entry to my blog. I think my new years resolution is to actually sit down and add something to my blog more often. Lets start this off with a little about what im doing.
Well as a Uni Student, I find myself finally moving into a flat. All students should go through the flatting experience, it&amp;rsquo;s character building and teaches you many valuable life skills, or so they say.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Post</title>
      <link>https://csmacnzblog.github.io/post/first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2007 01:28:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://csmacnzblog.github.io/post/first-post/</guid>
      <description>Ok, so all blogs start somewhere, and mine starts here with my first blog post. Welcome to everyone who has managed to find this site, it&amp;rsquo;s not that publicly advertised i know.
Firstly I would like to say a bit about myself. So I&amp;rsquo;m a 20 year old University Student at the University of Otago in New Zealand. I&amp;rsquo;m studying computers with quite vigorous passion, and on the side dabble in writing, music and a few other creative endeavors.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
