<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Lego on csMACnz&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.csmac.nz/tags/lego/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Lego on csMACnz&#39;s Blog</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://blog.csmac.nz/favicon.png</url>
      <title>csMACnz&#39;s Blog</title>
      <link>https://blog.csmac.nz</link>
    </image>
    <ttl>1440</ttl>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-nz</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2016 22:03:24 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.csmac.nz/tags/lego/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The art of the brick 2016</title>
      <link>https://blog.csmac.nz/post/the-art-of-the-brick-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2016 22:03:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.csmac.nz/post/the-art-of-the-brick-2016/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In 2008 (8 years ago!) &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.csmac.nz/the-art-of-the-brick/&#34;&gt;I blogged about the art of the brick&lt;/a&gt;. I didn&amp;rsquo;t join twitter until 2010, but if I had this probably wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have been a blog post, really, since I can fit it in a quote right here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check out this guy who makes art out of Lego bricks. Very talented and very creative, a must see. His name is Nathan Sawaya and he is a 33 year old New York artist. I really wish I could be in America to go see his art museum exhibit, the pictures on his website show some amazing sculptures. go check out &lt;a href=&#34;http://brickartist.com/&#34;&gt;The Art of the Brick&lt;/a&gt;. Well done mate. Thanks &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ursispaltenstein.ch/blog/weblog.php?/weblog/nathan_sawaya_the_art_of_the_brick/&#34;&gt;Ursi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So 8 years later I finally start my &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Overseas_experience&#34;&gt;Big OE&lt;/a&gt; traveling around Europe for a few years, first stop being Rome. And wouldn&amp;rsquo;t you know it, right down the road from my hotel is his &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.romeguide.it/?pag=mostre&amp;amp;tmo=mf&amp;amp;idmos=6246&amp;amp;lang=eng&#34;&gt;traveling exhibit&lt;/a&gt;!  It was up there with many of the other museums and galleries I&amp;rsquo;ve been to, just amazing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s more amazing is that I had forgotten I had written about this before. I knew the artist when I saw the post on the street and felt very lucky to finally see an exhibit that I thought I would never get to see (since I was living in &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/New_Zealand&#34;&gt;a small nation in the Pacific Ocean&lt;/a&gt;). But do you think I would recall that I had published something about him in the past?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is one of the reasons I blog. And talking to other bloggers they say the same. It is a record of things that I have discovered, figured out, and liked. It is for me, as a record that I can refer back to and find things to use again.  We blog first and foremost for ourselves. And the added benefit of doing so in a public forum is that like-minded people will be able to find value in it as well.  I can&amp;rsquo;t count the times I&amp;rsquo;ve searched something in Google only to find my own posts surfacing to the top.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For millennia humans have relied on one another to recall the minutiae of our daily goings-on. Now we rely on “the cloud”—and it is changing how we perceive and remember the world around us
&lt;cite&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.scientificamerican.com/article/the-internet-has-become-the-external-hard-drive-for-our-memories/&#34;&gt;Scientific American&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is why I blog. If you think there is a benefit to adding your own ideas to the global backup of our minds, maybe you should give it a try too?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information about Nathan Sawaya and his work, check out &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.artsy.net/artist/nathan-sawaya&#34;&gt;his artist&amp;rsquo;s page on artsy.net&lt;/a&gt;, and if you ever get the chance to view his works in person, I highly recommend it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The art of the brick</title>
      <link>https://blog.csmac.nz/post/the-art-of-the-brick/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2008 21:45:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.csmac.nz/post/the-art-of-the-brick/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Check out this guy who makes art out of Lego bricks. Very talented and very creative, a must see. His name is Nathan Sawaya and he is a 33 year old New York artist. I really wish I could be in America to go see his art museum exhibit, the pictures on his website show some amazing sculptures. go check out &lt;a href=&#34;http://brickartist.com/&#34;&gt;The Art of the Brick&lt;/a&gt;. Well done mate. Thanks &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ursispaltenstein.ch/blog/weblog.php?/weblog/nathan_sawaya_the_art_of_the_brick/&#34;&gt;Ursi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>