<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Personal on csMACnz&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.csmac.nz/tags/personal/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Personal on csMACnz&#39;s Blog</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://blog.csmac.nz/favicon.png</url>
      <title>csMACnz&#39;s Blog</title>
      <link>https://blog.csmac.nz</link>
    </image>
    <ttl>1440</ttl>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-nz</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2008 22:54:55 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.csmac.nz/tags/personal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Flatting: &#39;O&#39; week Arrivals</title>
      <link>https://blog.csmac.nz/post/flatting-o-week-arrivals/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2008 22:54:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.csmac.nz/post/flatting-o-week-arrivals/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The flat is finally full of people and things are starting to settle down and level off a bit.  It is now a week after &amp;lsquo;O&amp;rsquo; week, the biggest week on the University of Otago&amp;rsquo;s calender where all the students arrive back in dunedin, move into their flats and their Halls of Residence, and the orientation begins. Lectures have now begun and things are quieter, it is hard to tell that only a week ago everything was different.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The week before &amp;lsquo;O&amp;rsquo; week apprehension was in the air. The first of our flat mates arrived with all his stuff and started getting settled in. There were now three people in the flat and things stayed pretty quiet. A few days later the fourth person arrived and thats when the fun began. By now &amp;lsquo;O&amp;rsquo; week was but a few days away from beginning. It was Thursday night and it stayed pretty quiet, with a few drinks in the lounge.  Then we got a visit from a guy who if fondly known as SASQUATCH.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, Sasquatch is a great guy, but boy can he drink. And drink we did.  For a solid week, we sat on our front porch and drank out way through about 15 12-packs of Speights cans, a couple of boxes of Tui, a box of flame, and several bottles of various bourbons and spirits. We meet all our neighbours one way or another, as the wandered past and stopped to chat, or crossed the road and felt our shouts echoing around them down the street.  Evenings became prime poker time, and as we all sat around mellowing out and slowing down our intake slightly, we played a few friendly games, and a couple for money, and the week progressed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, I&amp;rsquo;m all for saving money by cooking, but I am also quite partial to getting fast food, because its convenient and, well, fast.  A stack of Dominoes Pizza boxes, almost as high as the door, was almost as much of an achievement for the week as the 3 full recycling bins, and the extra pile of cans and bottles behind it.  It is probably fair to say we live too close to the takeaway central, where you can find a McDonalds, a KFC, a Hells Pizza, Pizza Hut and Dominoes Pizza place, A liqueur Store, a Pub and 2 fish and chip shops.  I feel convenience will win out overall, if heart failure doesn&amp;rsquo;t beat it to the punch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The weekend brought about parties, and a long walk around town visiting various flat parties, flat warmings and flat drinks, which everyone claimed one of us knew a least one guy at each place.  This only lead to more free drinks from kegs and 24-packs, and a great way to end a great week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now everything is very studious. Lectures are being attended, tutorials and labs and starting up, recycling and rubbish has all been collected, and hangovers of past days are but a memory.  It is hard to even imagine that what I see before me is the same student-filled place of yester-week.  Truly this is Dunedin, The University City, &amp;lsquo;Get over It!&amp;rsquo; as they say.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Flatting Experience Continues</title>
      <link>https://blog.csmac.nz/post/the-flatting-experience-continues/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2008 02:26:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.csmac.nz/post/the-flatting-experience-continues/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s all starting to come together now. With power, phone and internet all connected and up and running, we can finally start living in our own flat. It has taken almost two weeks but finally we have our internet connected, and I can start using my computer more productively. As a Computing student, I really can say that I need the internet for my studies, and i can also claim that playing games helps my course, but of course this is easier to claim when I can do research on the internet. The next issue is to start running cables neatly around the house for the computers. We have one phone line in the house and it is located in the hallway. Unfortunately, the nearest power point on the other side of the hallway, so we need to run a phone cable across the hall to the modem, and that seems to block traffic just a bit too much. So we need to buy a decent length cable, and some cable clips to neatly run it around the walls so that it is no longer in the way, and doesn&amp;rsquo;t look bad. We did however buy a wireless router so we can reduce cables quite a lot by using wireless on all our computers. This is of course, except for my own desktop machine which I will have running as a streaming file server that, for sanity&amp;rsquo;s sake, needs to be wired. This has resulted in deciding upon getting a really long piece of ethernet cable and running it through the house. This too needs to be neatly pinned to the walls, because its bound to be tripped over otherwise, and that wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be good for the person tripping or my computer at the other end being pulled on. It seems that each problem we solve only leads to more problems. At least we have internet now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We finally have the flat to ourselves as well. The previous tenant has come to collect all his stuff, and in the process unlocking another room. We now have a key for every door (albeit a few locks aren&amp;rsquo;t the greatest) and are up to four house keys, thanks to the landlord who had spares of everything. We also got to the point we had set for the deadline for remaining items in the house to be claimable, so have acquired a large amount of kitchen-ware; pots, pans, utensils, cleaning products, plates, cups and cutlery. Then there was the food, at least two boxes full of non-perishables, and other items that we believe to be alright to eat, as well as some that I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure would kill me. And there was also a few heaters and other bits of furniture that we will no doubt make use of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So things are looking up in the flat, we still need to do cleaning, and the kitchen in now high priority, but there is no rush yet. It&amp;rsquo;s really starting to feel like home now.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Flatting Experience</title>
      <link>https://blog.csmac.nz/post/the-flatting-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2008 02:47:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.csmac.nz/post/the-flatting-experience/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ll I have officially been living in my flat for over a week, my first flat that i have lived in away from home, and so far I&amp;rsquo;ve enjoyed it. OK, so I haven&amp;rsquo;t really spent a great deal of time there, what with working all day and having a social life, but despite that it has been good so far. Maybe i should take a step back for a second.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is to be my third year away from home, my third attending the University of Otago in New Zealand, but my first living in a flat. For the last two years i have been living in a Hall of Residence. Think of it like boarding school accommodation, except more freedom, and less rules and strict people in charge. Anyway we had all our meals cooked for us, we had organised tutors for certain papers,organised recreational activities, and plenty of heat and power and security. So now I have&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;moved away from all that and am in a flat of five guys. We technically I&amp;rsquo;m in a flat with one other guy at the moment, the rest don&amp;rsquo;t move in for another month or so. The first issue we came across was getting the place looking tidy. It would seem that the previous tenants just walked out and left it in a right mess, with a lot of stuff left behind, including a full bedroom as messy as the day the guy lived in it. Well, we managed to clear enough stuff to make room to live in, but we still have a little way to go to get it all fixed up, including a lot of cleaning of cupboards and floors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next thing that we came across was getting all the utilities connected. The power hadn&amp;rsquo;t been disconnected from the last tenants, even though they had sent their disconnection notice in. So once I had called to set up the account in my name i thought we would be right. Unfortunately no-one had told the technician, who came the next morning while I was out and disconnected the power. A few angry phone calls and waiting around for half the day and he returned to fix it, at no extra cost to me. I should think so! Luckily the phone was a little easier to get connected and we had that up and running in one day. The internet is proving a little trickier, as they believe in making people wait, saying that it takes 5 to 10 business days to get it connected. As I write this we are on day 4, so hopefully tomorrow is the day, or I may be waiting another week without precious internet at my house. It&amp;rsquo;s a good thing that the university has internet and spare computers I can use or I would be in a right mess.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next issue that has arisen is keys. Doors need keys to lock and unlock them, but the thoughtless old tenants decided to take most of them with them when they left, leaving us with several problems. Problem one, we have one from door key between the two of us. Problem two, we cannot lock our bedrooms, and cannot unlock the other bedrooms. Problem three, someone out there has a key to my house, and therefore access to my stuff. It is slightly worrying to think about the third problem, so I&amp;rsquo;m going to ignore it for the moment. Again, it is lucky for us that the landlord has master keys for all the doors, and we can get in and out now that they have been supplied. The new problem this caused is that we now have the only keys to most of the doors. Why is this a problem for us you might be asking, well it is quite simple. If we loose our key, no one has another to let us back in. Maybe we should get more cut, that would be the sensible solution, but we are merely poor students as university, and we cannot afford to do such things when we feel it isn&amp;rsquo;t necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One week of flatting and so far the worst thing is that I have to do some cleaning. I guess that is easily remedied by just living with the mess. But If I want to have even the smallest resemblance of a social life, that just isn&amp;rsquo;t an option. maybe the tenant who left his room behind will do some cleaning when he comes to collect his stuff. At least we can get his keys back at some point, one less intruder to worry about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s going to be a fun year if every week is as eventful as the last one has been.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An ode to blogging</title>
      <link>https://blog.csmac.nz/post/an-ode-to-blogging/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2008 04:38:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.csmac.nz/post/an-ode-to-blogging/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A friend emailed me today, and told me a grand epic that was a day in his life, and my first response to him was &amp;lsquo;that story is blog-worthy, share it with the world why don&amp;rsquo;t you?&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s become more and more self-evident, that the world is full of linguistically capable, and even exceptional writers, many of whom would never have had a chance to use their gifts and let their unique genius be heard by others. But today, with the prominence of the internet, a uniquely powerful medium of free speech, anyone can have the opportunity to become the next great inspiring voice of tomorrow, following in the footsteps of people like Abraham Lincoln, Martin Luthor King, and even Buddha.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now we see some of these people rising through the polls of top 500 blogs around the web, and there are so many that their power, it would seem, is less then when they could have been singled out from the crowd. But in another way, they are able to share the power with others, and give more people the chance to be heard, and for better and greater freedom of choice from the people. Sure this also leads to extremist voices being a lot more vocal and in the foreground, but doesn&amp;rsquo;t that still mean that the balance of power remains even, that people still get the opportunity to freely choose the path less supported and more frowned upon? It seems that balance is one of the few constant things is this universe. I&amp;rsquo;m getting a&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;little side tracked here. The point of this blog post was to share with everyone my view on blogs, and blogging, and people sharing their every thought and feeling, and how great that is for the whole world to both give and receive, in the form of written language. My friend may just start his own blog, and if given permission, i will add a link to it from here for anyone out there reading my less then impressive blog (for now) may follow some of my influences, and perhaps learn something along the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So happy blogging to all, and i look forward to reading what people have done, thought, and experienced this week on the world wide web.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Web 2.0 people, it exists in all of us&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.oreillynet.com/pub/a/oreilly/tim/news/2005/09/30/what-is-web-20.html&#34; title=&#34;Tim Oreilly&#39;s &#39;What is web 2.0&#39;&#34;&gt;What is web 2.0?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s try this again</title>
      <link>https://blog.csmac.nz/post/lets-try-this-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jan 2008 21:09:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.csmac.nz/post/lets-try-this-again/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So I was on holiday, and over that time i didn&amp;rsquo;t add a single entry to my blog. I think my new years resolution is to actually sit down and add something to my blog more often. Lets start this off with a little about what im doing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well as a Uni Student, I find myself finally moving into a flat. All students should go through the flatting experience, it&amp;rsquo;s character building and teaches you many valuable life skills, or so they say. So I moved into my nice new flat, only to find that the last tenants practically just walked out at the end of last year. Ok, so there are some positives to that, such as well now have some of the essentials in the kitchen, including a lot of plates and cutlery, and a little bit of furniture we won&amp;rsquo;t have to buy. But the down side is that there is still stuff in the rooms, half the rooms are still locked, the fridge is still full of stuff that was once food, and nothing has been cleaned. I should also point out at this time that I am the first of five people to move into the flat, and no one else will arrive for another two months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a week of living in other peoples filth, finally one of the other people comes and starts to collect his stuff. We&amp;rsquo;ll it would seem that most of the other tenants are MIA, and that he has been left with the daunting task of cleaning the flat and moving things out. His answer to this was let me know what you guys what to keep in the flat and ill leave it behind for you. This also includes the odd thing that he wants to sell, but a lot that he will just give us. The landlord has finally got in touch with us too, after also being on holiday. So now we have a chance to get in some professional cleaners to fix up the place, a perhaps be able to get some livable space in there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This epic saga of the flatting experience continues, and hopefully gets better and not worse.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Post</title>
      <link>https://blog.csmac.nz/post/first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2007 01:28:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.csmac.nz/post/first-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ok, so all blogs start somewhere, and mine starts here with my first blog post. Welcome to everyone who has managed to find this site, it&amp;rsquo;s not that publicly advertised i know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly I would like to say a bit about myself.  So I&amp;rsquo;m a 20 year old University Student at the University of Otago in New Zealand.  I&amp;rsquo;m studying computers with quite vigorous passion, and on the side dabble in writing, music and a few other creative endeavors.  Music is my outlet for most of my creativity, and I hope to write and record some songs over the next year or 3 so keep and eye out for them in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I said I&amp;rsquo;m a computer science student, and because of that, expect a lot of my blogs to be about interesting technical stuff that I find around the internet and the goings on locally with me.  I will also try to review some of the software I try out, as well as gadgets, music, and whatever else tickles my fancy about the place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well that&amp;rsquo;s about right for an introduction and such, so my next blog will contain a bit more of a specific topic and maybe something that other people may actually want to know.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>