<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog Update on csMACnz&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://csmacnzblog.github.io/tags/blog-update/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog Update on csMACnz&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-nz</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2016 22:03:24 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://csmacnzblog.github.io/tags/blog-update/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The art of the brick 2016</title>
      <link>https://csmacnzblog.github.io/post/the-art-of-the-brick-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2016 22:03:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://csmacnzblog.github.io/post/the-art-of-the-brick-2016/</guid>
      <description>In 2008 (8 years ago!) I blogged about the art of the brick. I didn&amp;rsquo;t join twitter until 2010, but if I had this probably wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have been a blog post, really, since I can fit it in a quote right here:
 Check out this guy who makes art out of Lego bricks. Very talented and very creative, a must see. His name is Nathan Sawaya and he is a 33 year old New York artist.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time for an update</title>
      <link>https://csmacnzblog.github.io/post/time-for-an-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Sep 2010 08:33:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://csmacnzblog.github.io/post/time-for-an-update/</guid>
      <description>So I really should have posted something sooner, but I&amp;rsquo;ve been so busy with other things. Anyway, Change should soon be coming, I have a whole backlog of things i need to post about, and I&amp;rsquo;ve started using Twitter, which should result in this post being tweeted about due to a new plugin (fingers crossed). So here is my mental note, to myself and perhaps also a promise to the wider public, of what i hope to get done to this site over the next few months (I hope this is realistic enough :-) ).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An ode to blogging</title>
      <link>https://csmacnzblog.github.io/post/an-ode-to-blogging/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2008 04:38:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://csmacnzblog.github.io/post/an-ode-to-blogging/</guid>
      <description>A friend emailed me today, and told me a grand epic that was a day in his life, and my first response to him was &amp;lsquo;that story is blog-worthy, share it with the world why don&amp;rsquo;t you?&amp;rsquo;.
It&amp;rsquo;s become more and more self-evident, that the world is full of linguistically capable, and even exceptional writers, many of whom would never have had a chance to use their gifts and let their unique genius be heard by others.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
