<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog Update on csMACnz&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.csmac.nz/tags/blog-update/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog Update on csMACnz&#39;s Blog</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://blog.csmac.nz/favicon.png</url>
      <title>csMACnz&#39;s Blog</title>
      <link>https://blog.csmac.nz</link>
    </image>
    <ttl>1440</ttl>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-nz</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2021 20:30:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.csmac.nz/tags/blog-update/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>An almost seamless transition from Ghost to Hugo</title>
      <link>https://blog.csmac.nz/post/an-almost-seamless-transition-from-ghost-to-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2021 20:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.csmac.nz/post/an-almost-seamless-transition-from-ghost-to-hugo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well, I finally did it. Ghost has been sitting on an older version for a long time, my certs were expiring, and I did something about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tldr&#34;&gt;TL;DR;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My blog engine and hosting were deteriorating fast, so I moved to GitHub Pages, Hugo, and Static Site Generation, (mostly) without losing or breaking anything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;synopsys&#34;&gt;Synopsys&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Years ago I moved from WordPress to Ghost. This let me get on with writing and not worrying about the hosting. I moved it to Azure and even added a dynamic SSL certificate rotator using Lets Encrypt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eventually, the cert rotator broke, and the blog engine got enough major versions behind to make the upgrade path non-trivial to fix. Not to mention Google Ads decided my site wasn&amp;rsquo;t good enough for them and so disabled any ads that could have shown up. Hosting costs on Azure, while small, were a factor to think about too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Around the time I decided to do something about it, I also started paying attention to other people using static site generation to host their blogs. It didn&amp;rsquo;t take long to find a few really great articles that showed how simple this was going to be. The simplest of which seemed to be &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&#34;https://pages.github.com/&#34;&gt;GitHub Pages&lt;/a&gt;. So that is the path I went down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-went-well&#34;&gt;What went well&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My initial research was well-founded, and I very easily found the tool &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jbarone/ghostToHugo&#34;&gt;jbarone/ghostToHugo&lt;/a&gt; designed for the job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Initially, everything was super simple, and I had my content in Hugo in under an hour. Mainly I was following youngkin&amp;rsquo;s article: &lt;a href=&#34;https://youngkin.github.io/post/createafreeblogsite/&#34;&gt;Create a Free Blog Site Using GitHub Pages and Hugo&lt;/a&gt;, and then using ghostToHugo for my content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/getting-started/installing/&#34;&gt;Install Hugo CLI locally&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;create basis repository setup with the suggested theme &lt;a href=&#34;https://youngkin.github.io/post/createafreeblogsite/&#34;&gt;youngkin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ghost.org/help/the-importer/&#34;&gt;export my Ghost backup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;install &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jbarone/ghostToHugo&#34;&gt;ghostToHugo&lt;/a&gt; tool&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;run ghostToHugo to migrate posts into the site&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;run locally to test&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(I&amp;rsquo;m not repeating details here, because &lt;a href=&#34;https://youngkin.github.io/post/createafreeblogsite/&#34;&gt;youngkin&lt;/a&gt; has it nailed.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting this running on GitHub Pages was easy following that article too. Even setting a CNAME and DNS (a temporary subdomain while testing of course) was nice and easy to get working. (I use &lt;a href=&#34;https://dnsimple.com/&#34;&gt;DNSimple&lt;/a&gt;.) Job done. Right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-went-wrong&#34;&gt;What went wrong&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RSS.&lt;/strong&gt; My RSS feed has been a bit of an issue really. I knew it would probably break, and it wasn&amp;rsquo;t even available out of the box on Hugo either. So I fevered away adding RSS generation to the site generation and getting a fair approximation of my old feed. I knew it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be perfect, but I learned a bit about how the templating engine worked along the way. And when that hot cutover day came, it certainly failed. I had a few bugs to fix and all 50 people who have added this blog to their feed probably got a bit of a noisy mess. But hopefully, as they now read this article they now understand why. Also, there are now sub-categories with sub-category RSS feed URLs linked to from the right-hand sidebar now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Custom Theming.&lt;/strong&gt; I built my custom theme way back when I moved to Ghost. And I didn&amp;rsquo;t really feel like losing it. So I painstakingly mapped it from the Ghost templating engine to the one Hugo uses. This sucked. and it took ages (weeks) to get it right. Along the way, I probably did make some improvements that will be valuable later, like fixing the sidebar and better image handling possibilities. But this was probably the most time-consuming part of the whole process. In the end, retrologs&amp;rsquo; &lt;a href=&#34;https://retrolog.io/blog/creating-a-hugo-theme-from-scratch/&#34;&gt;Creating a Hugo Theme From Scratch&lt;/a&gt; was super useful at figuring out what went where, but I don&amp;rsquo;t actually understand some parts of the collection lookup code I wrote in some places yet. But it worked. At the very least, my CSS appears to have held the test of time (surprisingly!).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Permalinks.&lt;/strong&gt; Turns out Ghost had a few permalink redirect capabilities. And also the default URLs in Ghost were &lt;code&gt;/slug-for-page/&lt;/code&gt; while Hugo is &lt;code&gt;/post/slug-for-page/&lt;/code&gt;. Luckily the &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/content-management/urls/#aliases&#34;&gt;Aliases feature in Hugo&lt;/a&gt; allowed me to add both the draft/preview link (&lt;code&gt;/p/&amp;lt;GUID&amp;gt;/&lt;/code&gt;) as well as the old URL so that hopefully, no one loses my content, and instead get bounced to the right place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disqus.&lt;/strong&gt; See the comments at the bottom? I&amp;rsquo;ve been using Disqus to make them available. Turns out this was quite useful in moving to a static hosted solution. For the most part, this went well, because Disqus actually have a &lt;a href=&#34;https://help.disqus.com/en/articles/1717068-migration-tools&#34;&gt;migration tools feature&lt;/a&gt; available to use to move the URL associated with a page. The what went wrong part was that I prepared all the pages that looked like the normal post URL (&lt;code&gt;/slug-for-page/&lt;/code&gt;) before I cut over my DNS, but didn&amp;rsquo;t map any of the preview URLs (&lt;code&gt;/p/&amp;lt;GUID&amp;gt;/&lt;/code&gt;) across. I think what happened is that Ghost provided an id to Disqus as well as a URL, and it uses the first URL it sees as the identifying one. When I preview drafts, that preview URL is the one it saves. Since Hugo is just using the actual URL and not the id anymore, I lost my mapping over a few pages which I neglected to migrate. (My incorrect assumption was the draft ids didn&amp;rsquo;t have comments 😢.) I was without comments on some pages while I remedied that across a couple of evenings. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t too bad to put together a new CSV file for that though in the end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Google Ads.&lt;/strong&gt; Turns out they are still not happy with my website (and neither am I to be fair) so there is a bit more work to get them reenabled. It barely makes dollars a month, to be honest, but with it not working it makes a lot less of course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Content.&lt;/strong&gt; I spent far too much time looking at my content. While Ghost had tags, Hugo has both &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.csmac.nz/tags/&#34;&gt;Tags&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.csmac.nz/categories/&#34;&gt;Categories&lt;/a&gt;. I went through every historic post (193 over 13 and a half years if you can believe it) and updated many tags (deleting a bunch, adding a few) and creating categories for my content. I could have spent days (and still might) tidying up some of the content that never had any attention since coming out of WordPress and getting auto-converted to markdown all those years ago. But I held back, since I wanted to actually get this process done and back to writing. There was a little bit of work migrating some of the image functionality over too, but for the most part that was fine, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;summary&#34;&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Would I choose to do it again? Yes. I am certainly in a better place. So far, I think I&amp;rsquo;ve backed the right horse in Hugo. The workflow seems about as good as it was before, and I am aware of a few tools such as &lt;a href=&#34;https://cloudcannon.com/&#34;&gt;CloudCannon&lt;/a&gt; for better CMS management workflows if I desire. I might miss the Ghost app for drafts, but I mostly write on my desktop anyway. And since it is in GitHub, anything that can commit markdown to there is a way to draft.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that I have that done, the next step is likely to repeat the whole process with &lt;code&gt;csmac.nz&lt;/code&gt; as well and fix its certs, ads, and content. (That last one has been bugging me since I moved to Ghost to be fair&amp;hellip; &lt;code&gt;¯\_(ツ)_/¯&lt;/code&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The art of the brick 2016</title>
      <link>https://blog.csmac.nz/post/the-art-of-the-brick-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2016 22:03:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.csmac.nz/post/the-art-of-the-brick-2016/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In 2008 (8 years ago!) &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.csmac.nz/the-art-of-the-brick/&#34;&gt;I blogged about the art of the brick&lt;/a&gt;. I didn&amp;rsquo;t join twitter until 2010, but if I had this probably wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have been a blog post, really, since I can fit it in a quote right here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check out this guy who makes art out of Lego bricks. Very talented and very creative, a must see. His name is Nathan Sawaya and he is a 33 year old New York artist. I really wish I could be in America to go see his art museum exhibit, the pictures on his website show some amazing sculptures. go check out &lt;a href=&#34;http://brickartist.com/&#34;&gt;The Art of the Brick&lt;/a&gt;. Well done mate. Thanks &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ursispaltenstein.ch/blog/weblog.php?/weblog/nathan_sawaya_the_art_of_the_brick/&#34;&gt;Ursi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So 8 years later I finally start my &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Overseas_experience&#34;&gt;Big OE&lt;/a&gt; traveling around Europe for a few years, first stop being Rome. And wouldn&amp;rsquo;t you know it, right down the road from my hotel is his &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.romeguide.it/?pag=mostre&amp;amp;tmo=mf&amp;amp;idmos=6246&amp;amp;lang=eng&#34;&gt;traveling exhibit&lt;/a&gt;!  It was up there with many of the other museums and galleries I&amp;rsquo;ve been to, just amazing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s more amazing is that I had forgotten I had written about this before. I knew the artist when I saw the post on the street and felt very lucky to finally see an exhibit that I thought I would never get to see (since I was living in &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/New_Zealand&#34;&gt;a small nation in the Pacific Ocean&lt;/a&gt;). But do you think I would recall that I had published something about him in the past?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is one of the reasons I blog. And talking to other bloggers they say the same. It is a record of things that I have discovered, figured out, and liked. It is for me, as a record that I can refer back to and find things to use again.  We blog first and foremost for ourselves. And the added benefit of doing so in a public forum is that like-minded people will be able to find value in it as well.  I can&amp;rsquo;t count the times I&amp;rsquo;ve searched something in Google only to find my own posts surfacing to the top.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For millennia humans have relied on one another to recall the minutiae of our daily goings-on. Now we rely on “the cloud”—and it is changing how we perceive and remember the world around us
&lt;cite&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.scientificamerican.com/article/the-internet-has-become-the-external-hard-drive-for-our-memories/&#34;&gt;Scientific American&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is why I blog. If you think there is a benefit to adding your own ideas to the global backup of our minds, maybe you should give it a try too?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information about Nathan Sawaya and his work, check out &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.artsy.net/artist/nathan-sawaya&#34;&gt;his artist&amp;rsquo;s page on artsy.net&lt;/a&gt;, and if you ever get the chance to view his works in person, I highly recommend it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guess Who&#39;s Back?</title>
      <link>https://blog.csmac.nz/post/guess-whos-back/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2016 08:08:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.csmac.nz/post/guess-whos-back/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ok, so not that big a leap, it&amp;rsquo;s just me. Six months later me. Moved to the UK me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve taken the plunge and moved away from Windy Wellington in little old New Zealand to a place in the UK called &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.destinationmiltonkeynes.co.uk/&#34;&gt;Milton Keynes&lt;/a&gt;.  Famous for wide streets, round-a-bouts and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mkcows.com/&#34;&gt;concrete cows&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why Milton Keynes? Because Xero has an office here of course! Aside from being cheaper to live here than in the middle of London, it&amp;rsquo;s also a bit quieter and a bit of a slower pace of life for a bit, with reasonable connections to anywhere but here.  The plan is to live and work here for a while and travel around Great Britain and Europe. It makes sense when Europe is 2-3 hours aways from here when it was 26 hours of plane plus another 5-12 of airports from Wellington!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So as you can imagine, planning a move takes a while, and my Wife and I had a 7 week holiday on our way over. Thus explains the 6 months of no blog posts.  But I&amp;rsquo;m back in anger now and keen to get back into a good cadence of writing and GitHub-ing again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I travelled for the last 7 weeks, I completely lost touch with the development community. Partly from the busy sight-seeing schedule and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BEVzwZ7Fq1T/?taken-by=csmacnz&#34;&gt;picture taking&lt;/a&gt;, but partly because the mobile internet roaming charges were ridiculously priced, and hotel wifi was not amazing.  And I was on holiday, so no time for work. But it did have an unforeseen side effect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I spend 7 weeks around the non-geek, the computer normal, the general every-day average computer technology smart phone public. Real People. Lots of &amp;rsquo;em.  And I noticed a few things.  People have no idea what their devices can do. The times I heard &amp;ldquo;did you know it could do this?&amp;rdquo; for a years-old feature that came out 3 versions ago was interesting to hear. On top of this, the amount of bad software that people can and do put up with without complaining is amazing. We in the professional developer community hold other developers to a very high standard. One which we are very vocal about, but one the general public don&amp;rsquo;t really know to consider.  They put up with a lot, and are non-the-wiser.  Amazing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other side of travelling was using all of the hotel websites, airport touch kiosks and information centre devices.  Wow. Touch is hard, but some of these machines could do with a bit of TLC.  (What was I saying about high standards?)  It has made me appreciate good touch software when I see it, as well as sticking to good old keyboard or mouse over touch in some cases as well. I could type my name faster or select from a few dropdowns faster than using some of the touch-designed selections and wizards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For those of you making great experiences out there for travellers - thank you. For those of you making responsive web design - bravo. For those of you who realise people do have Windows Phones, even though we are only 5%, I applaud you!  And better yet, though of you who remember that as well as iPhone and Android apps, having a responsive web-based version for everyone else still covers the other 20-30% of phone users who still want to access your resources on their phone!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But now that I&amp;rsquo;m back, I can start my XAML windows development again, get stuck into &lt;a href=&#34;https://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/windows/uwp/get-started/whats-a-uwp&#34;&gt;Universal Windows Platform&lt;/a&gt; apps, and &lt;a href=&#34;http://dotnet.github.io/&#34;&gt;.Net Core&lt;/a&gt; development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who has an idea of an app gap I could fill? Send me a tweet or put a comment below and I might give it a go.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time for an update</title>
      <link>https://blog.csmac.nz/post/time-for-an-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Sep 2010 08:33:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.csmac.nz/post/time-for-an-update/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So I really should have posted something sooner, but I&amp;rsquo;ve been so busy with other things. Anyway, Change should soon be coming, I have a whole backlog of things i need to post about, and I&amp;rsquo;ve started using Twitter, which should result in this post being tweeted about due to a new plugin (fingers crossed). So here is my mental note, to myself and perhaps also a promise to the wider public, of what i hope to get done to this site over the next few months (I hope this is realistic enough :-) ).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finish Photo Album Application&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Restyle the site&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add twitter and Social Networking to my site&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Post about the HTML bridge&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Post about DataTemplateSelector&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Post about Attached Behaviour and default item selection&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Post about Blend and UI Styling&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create a Silverlight frontend for WordPress&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create Silverlight Tag Cloud&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And if i manage to get through all that I can probably afford to skip another month of not posting! lets see how we go aye?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An ode to blogging</title>
      <link>https://blog.csmac.nz/post/an-ode-to-blogging/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2008 04:38:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.csmac.nz/post/an-ode-to-blogging/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A friend emailed me today, and told me a grand epic that was a day in his life, and my first response to him was &amp;rsquo;that story is blog-worthy, share it with the world why don&amp;rsquo;t you?&#39;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s become more and more self-evident, that the world is full of linguistically capable, and even exceptional writers, many of whom would never have had a chance to use their gifts and let their unique genius be heard by others. But today, with the prominence of the internet, a uniquely powerful medium of free speech, anyone can have the opportunity to become the next great inspiring voice of tomorrow, following in the footsteps of people like Abraham Lincoln, Martin Luthor King, and even Buddha.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now we see some of these people rising through the polls of top 500 blogs around the web, and there are so many that their power, it would seem, is less then when they could have been singled out from the crowd. But in another way, they are able to share the power with others, and give more people the chance to be heard, and for better and greater freedom of choice from the people. Sure this also leads to extremist voices being a lot more vocal and in the foreground, but doesn&amp;rsquo;t that still mean that the balance of power remains even, that people still get the opportunity to freely choose the path less supported and more frowned upon? It seems that balance is one of the few constant things is this universe. I&amp;rsquo;m getting a&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;little side tracked here. The point of this blog post was to share with everyone my view on blogs, and blogging, and people sharing their every thought and feeling, and how great that is for the whole world to both give and receive, in the form of written language. My friend may just start his own blog, and if given permission, i will add a link to it from here for anyone out there reading my less then impressive blog (for now) may follow some of my influences, and perhaps learn something along the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So happy blogging to all, and i look forward to reading what people have done, thought, and experienced this week on the world wide web.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Web 2.0 people, it exists in all of us&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.oreillynet.com/pub/a/oreilly/tim/news/2005/09/30/what-is-web-20.html&#34; title=&#34;Tim Oreilly&#39;s &#39;What is web 2.0&#39;&#34;&gt;What is web 2.0?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s try this again</title>
      <link>https://blog.csmac.nz/post/lets-try-this-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jan 2008 21:09:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.csmac.nz/post/lets-try-this-again/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So I was on holiday, and over that time i didn&amp;rsquo;t add a single entry to my blog. I think my new years resolution is to actually sit down and add something to my blog more often. Lets start this off with a little about what im doing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well as a Uni Student, I find myself finally moving into a flat. All students should go through the flatting experience, it&amp;rsquo;s character building and teaches you many valuable life skills, or so they say. So I moved into my nice new flat, only to find that the last tenants practically just walked out at the end of last year. Ok, so there are some positives to that, such as well now have some of the essentials in the kitchen, including a lot of plates and cutlery, and a little bit of furniture we won&amp;rsquo;t have to buy. But the down side is that there is still stuff in the rooms, half the rooms are still locked, the fridge is still full of stuff that was once food, and nothing has been cleaned. I should also point out at this time that I am the first of five people to move into the flat, and no one else will arrive for another two months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a week of living in other peoples filth, finally one of the other people comes and starts to collect his stuff. We&amp;rsquo;ll it would seem that most of the other tenants are MIA, and that he has been left with the daunting task of cleaning the flat and moving things out. His answer to this was let me know what you guys what to keep in the flat and ill leave it behind for you. This also includes the odd thing that he wants to sell, but a lot that he will just give us. The landlord has finally got in touch with us too, after also being on holiday. So now we have a chance to get in some professional cleaners to fix up the place, a perhaps be able to get some livable space in there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This epic saga of the flatting experience continues, and hopefully gets better and not worse.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Post</title>
      <link>https://blog.csmac.nz/post/first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2007 01:28:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.csmac.nz/post/first-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ok, so all blogs start somewhere, and mine starts here with my first blog post. Welcome to everyone who has managed to find this site, it&amp;rsquo;s not that publicly advertised i know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly I would like to say a bit about myself.  So I&amp;rsquo;m a 20 year old University Student at the University of Otago in New Zealand.  I&amp;rsquo;m studying computers with quite vigorous passion, and on the side dabble in writing, music and a few other creative endeavors.  Music is my outlet for most of my creativity, and I hope to write and record some songs over the next year or 3 so keep and eye out for them in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I said I&amp;rsquo;m a computer science student, and because of that, expect a lot of my blogs to be about interesting technical stuff that I find around the internet and the goings on locally with me.  I will also try to review some of the software I try out, as well as gadgets, music, and whatever else tickles my fancy about the place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well that&amp;rsquo;s about right for an introduction and such, so my next blog will contain a bit more of a specific topic and maybe something that other people may actually want to know.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>