<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Statistics on csMACnz&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://csmacnzblog.github.io/tags/statistics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Statistics on csMACnz&#39;s Blog</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://csmacnzblog.github.io/favicon.png</url>
      <title>csMACnz&#39;s Blog</title>
      <link>https://csmacnzblog.github.io</link>
    </image>
    <ttl>1440</ttl>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-nz</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2015 11:13:12 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://csmacnzblog.github.io/tags/statistics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Visual Studio 2015 vs Visual Studio 2013</title>
      <link>https://csmacnzblog.github.io/post/visual-studio-2015-vs-visual-studio-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2015 11:13:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://csmacnzblog.github.io/post/visual-studio-2015-vs-visual-studio-2013/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been running some numbers over our solution to try and make things more efficient. While I was at it, I figured I would put 2013 head to head with 2015.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main test I ran was to take a solution open in Visual Studio and make sure it builds. I then ran Clean Solution.  Using a stopwatch (so accuracy +- 1-second values) I recorded how long it took to build. I repeated this 5 times, over three machines, once each with 2013 and 2015.  So first, the raw numbers (in seconds):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The average results from this looks like so:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And for completeness, I thought I would graph the data as well:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://res.cloudinary.com/csmacnz/image/upload/v1438810998/VSBuildGraph_gsk2nx.png&#34; alt=&#34;Visual Studio Build times comparing 2013 to 2015 across devices.&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;conclusions&#34;&gt;Conclusions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Across the board, we have significate improvements. Visual Studio 2015 is just faster. And since nothing obvious breaks for my solution, at this stage I will be using it as the faster choice going forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This test only ran across one solution with 30 C# projects, across 3 very similar machines, only 5 times each. For a more conclusive answer, you would want to run this across a whole range of extra solutions and machines. But from this limited view, I&amp;rsquo;m really impressed by the perf increase of builds that 2015 provides me, for my particular code base, at this point in time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;other-findings&#34;&gt;Other Findings&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During this exercise of measuring I can across one other nice conclusion as well. Restoring NuGet packages on a large solution with a complex dependency graph is much faster when using the command line, rather than letting visual studio load them on demand right before a build.  I didn&amp;rsquo;t get any hard numbers yet, but it feels significant. It took 2-4 minutes for VS to finish loading NuGet packages before it started building, versus the same dependencies loaded from the command line in 20 or 30 seconds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-powershell&#34;&gt;nuget restore src\mySolution.sln
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is true that I am using a locally hosted NuGet 2 server, and that could be a factor, so your mileage may vary. But I usually find that command line tasks do come out faster compared to GUI ones, and this is one I will change my habits over.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>