<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Microsoft on csMACnz&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.csmac.nz/tags/microsoft/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Microsoft on csMACnz&#39;s Blog</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://blog.csmac.nz/favicon.png</url>
      <title>csMACnz&#39;s Blog</title>
      <link>https://blog.csmac.nz</link>
    </image>
    <ttl>1440</ttl>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-nz</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2017 23:50:24 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.csmac.nz/tags/microsoft/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft &amp; Google, Android Wear support is missing</title>
      <link>https://blog.csmac.nz/post/microsoft-google-android-wear-support-is-missing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2017 23:50:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.csmac.nz/post/microsoft-google-android-wear-support-is-missing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ok, so I know I am in the minority as a Windows Phone user, but sometimes I just get frustrated and I wish Microsoft at least tried to achieve parity with their platforms, and not leave it to others who just won&amp;rsquo;t bother.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a really nice &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.microsoftstore.com/store/msuk/en_GB/pdp/Acer-Liquid-Jade-Primo--Unlocked/productID.5064103000&#34;&gt;Acer Liquid Jade Primo&lt;/a&gt; Windows 10 mobile phone. Continuum, Hexa Core Processor, 3GB memory, nice 5.5&amp;quot; screen, great camera.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I went shopping and saw the really nice Fossil Q watches. (Further disclaimer: I already own a really nice Fossil Mechanical watch, and a Microsoft Band 2) They were really nice, but I had to walk away. Why? Because they run Android Wear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, technically, there is no limitation that says &amp;ldquo;because it is Android, it will not work with Windows&amp;rdquo;. It has even been &lt;a href=&#34;https://mspoweruser.com/developer-working-making-android-wear-work-windows-10-mobile/&#34;&gt;proven possible&lt;/a&gt; by an independent developer talking to the Bluetooth APIs, and Windows has some really nice API hooks already to allow smart devices to hook into many parts of messaging and notifications. It&amp;rsquo;s just that Google has no inclination to write a Windows Phone 8 or Windows 10 UWP app that supports it. They wrote an iPhone app, though. Because otherwise how will their hardware and software compete with the Apple Watch?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What makes me frustrated isn&amp;rsquo;t that Google isn&amp;rsquo;t supporting Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s business plan, and the progress of their competitor to Android, It is actually that Microsoft doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem to be doing anything to provide these missing applications themselves. If you are willing to write apps for Android Wear, then why not allow those apps the chance to work with a Windows Phone?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Microsoft Research, I would love to see you release something awesome in the Android-Wear client app space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just one more stone on the scales tipping them in the wrong direction that might one day force me to buy an Android.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;/rant&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Band 2 - The first 24 hours</title>
      <link>https://blog.csmac.nz/post/microsoft-band-2-the-first-24-hours/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2015 09:13:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.csmac.nz/post/microsoft-band-2-the-first-24-hours/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My Microsoft Band finally arrived yesterday morning, so obviously I put it straight on (after a charge of course). Here is a chronicle of first impressions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://res.cloudinary.com/csmacnz/image/upload/c_scale,w_800/v1447883120/microsoftbandunboxed_qlnuof.png&#34; alt=&#34;Unboxing the device.&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;setup&#34;&gt;Setup&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Out of the box, setup was really easy. Simply following the instructions on the band and the phone made it simple. I paired it with my Windows Phone (a Lumia 930) and as soon as the connection was made, the two devices started to chat to each other, downloading updates for the band using my phone&amp;rsquo;s internet connection. Very Internet of Things. Once that was complete I played around with the apps and tiles available, configuring the ones I wanted and turning off ones I didn&amp;rsquo;t (like Starbucks and Twitter).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;first-impressions&#34;&gt;First impressions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At first after putting it on it was a little uncomfortable, since I am wearing it on my right wrist and I have always worn my watch on my left.  This quickly passed and I barely felt it anymore after that. I turned on txt and email alerts and started getting a buzz on my wrist every time an email or txt came in. Notifications also came through to the Band as well. Haptic alerts can be adjusted to the strength that works for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was able to use the on-screen keyboard to reply to txt messages, and played with some Cortana searches such as &amp;ldquo;remind me to buy milk on the way home&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;what am I doing tonight&amp;rdquo;. Simple commands relay the Cortana results back to the Band. Other more complex results such as search results would direct you to look at your phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;telling-the-time&#34;&gt;Telling the time&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The band does have a watch mode, but I don&amp;rsquo;t think I&amp;rsquo;ll use it for now. First, I still wear an analog watch on my left write, but the second is power consumption. The Always On mode means you can treat it like a regular watch when you&amp;rsquo;re not interacting with it. The caveat is that it uses more power. There is a Rotate On mode as well, which will flash up the time when you flick your wrist around to look at the Band. I was finding that this was triggered more often than I wanted it to be, and was distracting, so the setting is now Off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;speed-reading&#34;&gt;Speed reading&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A feature I didn&amp;rsquo;t know the band had been Speed Reading. When a message is displayed, you can scroll up and down and read it yourself. If you press the Action button It will display one word at a time for you to read in a speed reading fashion. I quite enjoyed the settings available for speed: Off, Slower, Slow, Medium, Fast and Faster. My current setting is Fast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;sleep&#34;&gt;Sleep&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a Fitbit. It&amp;rsquo;s the Fitbit One model, that comes with a belt clip case, and a velcro arm wrist that you can slot it into to track your sleep. That lasted about 3 weeks before it was too much hassle changing the case over every night and every morning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last night I wore the Band to bed. Sleep mode is easy to turn on and produced some interesting results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://res.cloudinary.com/csmacnz/image/upload/c_scale,w_600/v1447883206/wp_ss_20151119_0001_qaj7zn.png&#34; alt=&#34;Sleep tracking results.&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, the alarm I set for 7 am woke me up at 6:30.  This is the Smart Alarm feature, that decides the optimal time to wake you up. Sure. I guess I was kind of awake anyway? It does seem to think I had 90% efficiency in my sleep, even if I did only get 6 hours. Again, I suppose I feel rested? I do seem to wake up a lot in the night. It will be interesting to see what this looks like over time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;walking-to-work&#34;&gt;Walking to work&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This morning I took the Run mode for a spin while walking to work. Yeah, I was only walking, but still it is interesting to see my heart rate changing, and the GPS tracking my location.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://res.cloudinary.com/csmacnz/image/upload/c_scale,w_600/v1447884169/wp_ss_20151119_0002_bt8nf7.png&#34; alt=&#34;Walking to work tracking.&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;battery&#34;&gt;Battery&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not sure If I gave it a full charge or not, but only just now has it given me a low battery warning. That&amp;rsquo;s pretty good for a first-day use, especially while I was playing with it much more than I might on a standard day. So day 1, that&amp;rsquo;s 24-26 hours of power. Time will tell if I end up averaging more or less, and how long a charge I need to give it to get that benefit back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;in-conclusion&#34;&gt;In Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m glad I bought it. And I&amp;rsquo;ll be sure to recommend it as a reasonable alternative to a Fitbit, or sports watch.  Next steps, go for a real run with it and monitor my stats over the next few weeks. All going well I&amp;rsquo;ll pull down the SDK and figure out how to turn it into a remote for audio playback&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Releases Application Bar Icons for Windows Phone 7</title>
      <link>https://blog.csmac.nz/post/microsoft-releases-application-bar-icons-for-windows-phone-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Apr 2010 05:16:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.csmac.nz/post/microsoft-releases-application-bar-icons-for-windows-phone-7/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://erictric.com/2010/04/07/microsoft-releases-application-bar-icons-for-windows-phone-7/&#34; title=&#34;Microsoft Releases Application Bar Icons for Windows Phone 7&#34;&gt;Check out the icons&lt;/a&gt; for developers, For Windows Phone 7, lookin pretty sharp.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>