<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Recipe on csMACnz&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://csmacnzblog.github.io/categories/recipe/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Recipe on csMACnz&#39;s Blog</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://csmacnzblog.github.io/favicon.png</url>
      <title>csMACnz&#39;s Blog</title>
      <link>https://csmacnzblog.github.io</link>
    </image>
    <ttl>1440</ttl>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-nz</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Mar 2010 23:01:57 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://csmacnzblog.github.io/categories/recipe/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Delicious Mussels Recipe</title>
      <link>https://csmacnzblog.github.io/post/delicious-mussels-recipe/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Mar 2010 23:01:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://csmacnzblog.github.io/post/delicious-mussels-recipe/</guid>
      <description><p>Yesterday at the supermarket, Mussels just happened to be on special, and after the last meal of Mussels I had cooked for me turned out so great, I thought I would give them a go. First things first, I had no recipe so performed some quick google magic and stubbled upon this great, simple recipe for Creamy Garlic &amp; White Wine Mussels. <strong>Prep time:</strong> 20 minutes <strong>Cook time:</strong> 5 minutes <strong>Servings:</strong> 2 <strong>Ingredients:</strong> 1 dozen green lip mussels 6 cloves of garlic 1 1/2 cups of white wine (SauvignonBlanc worked well for me) 1 stalk of celery 1 small onion 1 tablespoon butter (but the more the better I found) 1/4 cup of cream (Maybe add a little more if you like a creamier broth, I&rsquo;m keen to try coconut cream next time) **Directions:**<strong>Preparing mussels for cooking</strong> Scrub mussels well in sink with running cold water. Remove &ldquo;beards&rdquo; from the mussel by pulling firmly towards hinge. If mussels are open then tap them&hellip;if they close they are good but if the do not discard immediately. 1. Finely chopped onion, celery and garlic. Place into pot and gently sauté in butter. (Make sure the pot is big enough to hold the dozen mussels). 2. Add the wine and bring to the boil. Drop in mussels, stir once and place on the lid. Steam until they open. Discard any that do not open. 3. Remove pot from heat, add cream and serve. Best served with some crusty french bread to soak up the delicious sauce. A simple, straightforward recipe that went off without a hitch, definitely recommend giving this one a go, especially if you can get a dozen Mussels for NZ$1.50 like I did. The most expensive part of this meal is the wine! The original recipe can be found <a href="http://www.kiwiwise.co.nz/recipe/mussels-white-wine">here</a></p>
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>